<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>P's blog</title><link href="https://princiya.com/newblog/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://princiya.com/newblog/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://princiya.com/newblog/</id><updated>2022-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>Archives from princiya.com/blog</title><link href="https://princiya.com/newblog/archives-from-princiyacomblog.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Princiya Sequeira</name></author><id>tag:princiya.com,2022-12-31:/newblog/archives-from-princiyacomblog.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is my new blog home based on Pelican.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href="./hello-pelican"&gt;hello-pelican&lt;/a&gt; post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, all old posts are &lt;a href="https://princiya.com/blog"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. I hope to migrate all of them to one place, soon!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Javascript"></category><category term="blog"></category></entry><entry><title>Dump of my blog topics</title><link href="https://princiya.com/newblog/dump-of-my-blog-topics.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-12-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-12-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Princiya Sequeira</name></author><id>tag:princiya.com,2022-12-01:/newblog/dump-of-my-blog-topics.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Blog topics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lessons from parenthood for engineering leadership&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Navigating through chaos / Interruption driven development
How to get better at it or embrace chaos&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onboarding for new EMs
Remote first and onboarding&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tech hiring. Good and Bad&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DB - memory
Performance - reviews
Everything is tied around people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reset &amp;amp; recharge - humans need it …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Blog topics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lessons from parenthood for engineering leadership&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Navigating through chaos / Interruption driven development
How to get better at it or embrace chaos&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onboarding for new EMs
Remote first and onboarding&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tech hiring. Good and Bad&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DB - memory
Performance - reviews
Everything is tied around people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reset &amp;amp; recharge - humans need it too just like devices!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Design patterns against people&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intereview &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;what it is like to be a woman in tech in a leadership position&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Promotion justification: Vijesh example&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does my day look like
How many hours I work weekly?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do I manage side projects&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do I run my 1:1s&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working with product, principal, coach&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Experience coming from a non Python world&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working closely with QA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How much do I know for my team - infra, python, tech, code, product, &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B2B vs B2C&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do people absorb information - filters applied all the time. We need to repeat and then people process based on how they hear&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working with the services team&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Metrics vs no metrics&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How did I work in the absence of PO and AC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Performance review notes captured in slack&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do I organise myself —&amp;gt; slack&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strength finder&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WWCode fellow experience&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WWCode —&amp;gt; what worked, what did not&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What to learn series&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Values &amp;amp; culture round —&amp;gt; how do I judge candidates
What is red? How do I update my notes with supporting answers
What questions to pick —&amp;gt; pick questions that I am comfortable with and clear on red flags.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My authentic leadership style&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be selfish&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My areas to improvements&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mistakes I have made&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reverse mentoring&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do I look for in CV?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do I do in my EM screen call?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knowledge sharing x10&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do what matters&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lightbeam topics&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things that I am proud of&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is next for me&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do I do when I get a break&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;35 things before 35
Mentioned in Forbes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bucket list&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Newsletters I follow&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lessons from leaddev &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leader vs Manager&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Polling vs web sockets&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How to identify gaps
BelleSukanya
Jak&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;STAR situation task action result&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zero to one and my dunning Krueger effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Career FOMO - initial years easy to get promoted. Later years, it is hard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How to be a tie-breaker? EM question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marshmallow challenge and analogy to the architecture&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interview burnout&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Babysitting the team
How to communicate 1:1 to people and see if they self-organise?
Ramp up the team at the same pace as I want to grow&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take criticism as feedback:
Great critics from Jesus.
Fighting with critics&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlearn from having to do every item from checklist to get to next level&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BICEPS
Belonging, improvement, choice, equality, predictability, significance&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How to make time for conferences?
https://anaconda.slack.com/archives/C042Q107AA0/p1669118882385749&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How to have healthy PR conversations?
You deserve to be paid fairly with regard to the level you are at and the work you do. You deserve to be leveled properly based on the value you contribute. Every worker deserves this.
Also, when you are tracking the work you've done, you can have a long list of things you did (activity), or you can have a long list of outcomes you made happen (value delivered). You will get paid / promoted on value you delivered. (If you are in a healthy system.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Negotiating raises:
I have many thoughts on raises, but my tactics vary depending on my company and my role. In very early stage startups, there are usually no salary bands, not guidance, nor any formal review process. In those situations, I ask my boss for raises often, generally after I do a thing that brings a lot of value to the company.
In more mature companies, where there are review processes, salary bands and the like, I find it's more about advocacy for myself and what I have done within the context of the company process. I always want to be sure I'm fairly leveled compared to my peers. Also, having others advocate for you is important. Who are your allies? How do they help highlight your contributions? When you work on off-team efforts (guilds, hiring revamp, etc.), who sees that work? Are they relaying feedback to your manager, etc.?
I know it can feel tough to advocate for yourself, and that it takes practice doing that for it to feel less icky. But I often coach my engineers to do just that. Understanding the value of your labor in the market is important. Knowing what others who do what you do make in your region is important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Motivation - Hygiene theory at work
Motivation factors include: challenging work; recognition for one’s achievements; responsibility; the opportunity to do something meaningful; involvement in decision making; and a sense of importance to the organization. On the other hand, hygiene factors include: salary; work conditions; company policy and administration; supervision; working relationships; status and security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ADHD and emotional intelligence&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Techblog:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;S3 migration from EFS
AS tech concepts, mirroring, eve, sbom
Kendo PoC
BDD QA&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Draft"></category><category term="notes"></category></entry><entry><title>My Leadership Strengths</title><link href="https://princiya.com/newblog/my-leadership-strengths.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-11-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-11-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Princiya Sequeira</name></author><id>tag:princiya.com,2022-11-01:/newblog/my-leadership-strengths.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My Top 5 Themes
1. Strategic
2. Relator
3. Achiever
4. Learner
5. Responsibility&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Strategic&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People who are especially talented in the Strategic theme create alternative ways to proceed. Faced with any given scenario, they can quickly spot the relevant patterns and issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I too indentify being strategic is one …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My Top 5 Themes
1. Strategic
2. Relator
3. Achiever
4. Learner
5. Responsibility&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Strategic&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People who are especially talented in the Strategic theme create alternative ways to proceed. Faced with any given scenario, they can quickly spot the relevant patterns and issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I too indentify being strategic is one of my biggest strengths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://www.lenareinhard.com/articles/how-to-lead-strategically-every-day&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Relator&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People who are especially talented in the Relator theme enjoy close relationships with others. They find deep satisfaction in working hard with friends to achieve a goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Achiever&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People who are especially talented in the Achiever theme have a great deal of stamina and work hard. They take great satisfaction from being busy and productive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Learner&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People who are especially talented in the Learner theme have a great desire to learn and want to continuously improve. In particular, the process of learning, rather than the outcome, excites them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Responsibility&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People who are especially talented in the Responsibility theme take psychological ownership of what they say they will do. They are committed to stable values such as honesty and loyalty.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Leadership"></category><category term="notes"></category></entry><entry><title>What is humility</title><link href="https://princiya.com/newblog/what-is-humility.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-09-15T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-09-15T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Princiya Sequeira</name></author><id>tag:princiya.com,2022-09-15:/newblog/what-is-humility.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Humility is the anecdote to arrogance. Humility is a recognition that we don’t know, that we were wrong, that we’re not better than anyone else.
Humility is simple to understand but hard to practice.
Humility isn’t a lack of confidence but an earned confidence. The confidence to …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Humility is the anecdote to arrogance. Humility is a recognition that we don’t know, that we were wrong, that we’re not better than anyone else.
Humility is simple to understand but hard to practice.
Humility isn’t a lack of confidence but an earned confidence. The confidence to say that you might not be right, but you’ve done the diligence, and you’ve put in the work.
Humility keeps you wondering what you’re missing or if someone is working harder than you. And yet when pride and arrogance take over, humility flees and so does our ability to learn, adapt, and build lasting relationships with others.
Humility won’t let you take credit for luck. And humility is the voice in your mind that doesn’t let small victories seem larger than they are. Humility is the voice inside your head that says, ‘anyone can do it once, that’s luck. Can you do it consistently?’
More than knowing yourself, humility is accepting yourself.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Draft"></category><category term="notes"></category></entry><entry><title>What is the EM aka Engineering Manager role?</title><link href="https://princiya.com/newblog/what-is-the-em-aka-engineering-manager-role.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-09-15T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-09-15T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Princiya Sequeira</name></author><id>tag:princiya.com,2022-09-15:/newblog/what-is-the-em-aka-engineering-manager-role.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Business Impact - Clear business metrics and working towards ambitious goals 
● Team Health - Team members are engaged and complement each other in achieving common goals autonomously 
● Productivity - MVP mindset, continuous improvements of team ways of working 
● Systems Health - Defining and delivering towards clear metrics and SLOs 
● Stakeholder Happiness - Managing dependencies and …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Business Impact - Clear business metrics and working towards ambitious goals 
● Team Health - Team members are engaged and complement each other in achieving common goals autonomously 
● Productivity - MVP mindset, continuous improvements of team ways of working 
● Systems Health - Defining and delivering towards clear metrics and SLOs 
● Stakeholder Happiness - Managing dependencies and expectations, building trust with all stakeholders and delivering on commitments The above can be summarized as getting things done and the supporting activities that enable a high performing team environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;all things tech and strategy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Core skills for engineering leadership:
- Developing team
- Building culture
- Tackling difficult conversations
- Remedying underperformance
- Managing up and influencing
- Personal development&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People leadership&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tech acumen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to deliver&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Business impact&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Process design 
Have a “board of advisors”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a manager and leader, you’ll coach and develop the team, providing regular feedback, and helping each individual to learn, grow and develop their career. You’ll work closely with product managers, design, and engineers to influence product direction, always keeping quality and the experience of developers top-of-mind with a relentless focus on excellence in user experience. You’ll help shape an environment of psychological safety which values experimentation and continuous learning. You’ll influence and provide feedback on the organizational culture and processes, always looking for opportunities to improve in a continuous pursuit for excellence.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Leadership"></category><category term="notes"></category></entry><entry><title>Job hunting advice for beginners</title><link href="https://princiya.com/newblog/job-hunting-advice-for-beginners.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-09-07T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-09-07T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Princiya Sequeira</name></author><id>tag:princiya.com,2022-09-07:/newblog/job-hunting-advice-for-beginners.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Regarding the article that I mentioned about a portfolio website is not important while applying for your first developer job, &lt;a href="https://profy.dev/article/portfolio-websites-survey"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; is the link to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to that, as I mentioned during the call, focus on your learnings and convince the hiring manager of how much learning you …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Regarding the article that I mentioned about a portfolio website is not important while applying for your first developer job, &lt;a href="https://profy.dev/article/portfolio-websites-survey"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; is the link to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to that, as I mentioned during the call, focus on your learnings and convince the hiring manager of how much learning you have done until now and are willing to do. From my personal experience, when I hire for junior positions all I look for is their attitude for learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With regards to your other question regarding what core fundamentals are required to be a great front-end developer:
For the beginner level, it's all about how quickly you are able to grasp new concepts, demonstrate a willingness to learn, and iterate over them. &lt;a href="https://www.joshwcomeau.com/blog/how-to-learn-stuff-quickly/"&gt;This&lt;/a&gt; is a good article on how to learn things quickly.
As you are learning, you will eventually figure out the things that you are interested in and would want to learn more of that, practice, and get better.
Your peers and the job itself might show you new opportunities and you need to be ready to step out of your comfort zone, work on those, ask questions and learn new things on the fly. The learning pattern gets built this way.
As you are learning and exploring, try to establish a pattern where you understand the 'why' behind what you are doing. The 'how' part is usually covered by tutorials, searching on the internet, etc. It is being able to understand the 'why' behind what you are doing will help you learn things faster and let you connect the dots as you get introduced to newer concepts and topics. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/chrishlad/status/1424704009424752646"&gt;This&lt;/a&gt; is a nice tweet on exponential learning.
In &lt;a href="https://roadmap.sh/frontend"&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; article, you will find a broader range of topics for a front-end developer. But the core of it will be HTML, Vanilla JavaScript and CSS. Using libraries or frameworks will always be in addition to these core concepts, and the kind of topics that you will get to work with will depend on your job, your team, the product. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What applications should I apply for as a beginner? Are there any keywords I should be looking out for?
Look out for jobs that explicitly hire for junior roles. Some of the questions to ask your hiring manager would be the following:
- do you offer mentorship? this is very important because as a junior you need good support from the team for onboarding and mentorship
- is there a learning budget? or is there time to learn new things as part of the job? this is important too because when you are a beginner you need mentorship + time to learn new things. it should not be that you just fix bugs or work on new features for the product/company and learning is not given importance. You will then end up being overwhelmed, or not enjoy your work over the long term when you cannot learn and grow.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2) Do you have dev job website recommendations?
none in particular. the best way to apply as a beginner is through networking or connections. talk to people, join communities and discover opportunities. when you know someone working at a company and if they are able to refer you internally the process is faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3) Do you have an example of an outstanding resume I can see?
I don't have one. But you can send me yours and I can review it. For beginners, I would prefer a one-page format (not a hard rule, but better). List your academic or self-study coursework relevant to the job you are applying for, list 2-3 projects that you worked on, mention what tools and tech stack you used, and most importantly highlight in your project work a specific problem you would have solved, the things that you are proud of.
A resume is your marketing pitch to the recruiter/hiring manager, so give a thought about the message that you want to convey and capture their attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resume:
————-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to what we spoke about regarding the resume, the below links might be useful to give you more context. Wish you all the best.
https://www.linkedin.com/learning/writing-a-tech-resume/how-hiring-managers-read-your-resumehttps://thetechresume.com/&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Mentoring"></category><category term="advice"></category><category term="career"></category></entry><entry><title>How to handle anxiety at work?</title><link href="https://princiya.com/newblog/how-to-handle-anxiety-at-work.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-09-01T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-09-01T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Princiya Sequeira</name></author><id>tag:princiya.com,2022-09-01:/newblog/how-to-handle-anxiety-at-work.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am going through a lot of stress and anxiety these days and also I switched to new job. I am unable to perform since I am not focussed. Also taking some counselling. My manager has appointed a team lead to work with me daily for 2 hour and now …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am going through a lot of stress and anxiety these days and also I switched to new job. I am unable to perform since I am not focussed. Also taking some counselling. My manager has appointed a team lead to work with me daily for 2 hour and now gives me regular feedback, they pin point me for very small thing now. I feel somehow my job is not secured. Can I gave my this reason to employer for stress and anxiety as a reason to them for not being able to concentrate.? Will it secure my job ? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Answer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not to conflict with what others have said above, I truly respect the answers above. Here is my take, especially being a manager.
I would truly appreciate if you could be as honest and transparent to your manager, I don't know your manager, but this is what I would wish from my direct reports.
I had a similar case, where my report had to go on a long medical leave and I truly supported that. You can talk to your doctor and ask for a special letter which will let you take leave for up to 6 weeks, beyond which (I am not very sure, something to check with the HR) I think it goes unpaid or is partially covered from your health insurance.
But in your case, since you are in the probationary period, I assume because its mentioned you started a new job recently, going on a longer medical leave might backfire against you&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Mentoring"></category><category term="advice"></category><category term="career"></category></entry><entry><title>Is career in tech high pressure?</title><link href="https://princiya.com/newblog/is-career-in-tech-high-pressure.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-08-31T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-08-31T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Princiya Sequeira</name></author><id>tag:princiya.com,2022-08-31:/newblog/is-career-in-tech-high-pressure.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to hear your opinion/experience on whether a career in tech is high pressure, depending on whether the role is in a startup, consultancy or something else(?). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Today I had to attend a job interview with a start-up while my kid was with me. The first question the …&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to hear your opinion/experience on whether a career in tech is high pressure, depending on whether the role is in a startup, consultancy or something else(?). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Today I had to attend a job interview with a start-up while my kid was with me. The first question the interviewer asked me how my family situation is and whether I'll be able to handle (crazy) pressure. Then he went on how he's fed up with the work culture of people, especially data scientists in his team who moved from academia.
To be honest, I've interviewed with a lot of people when my child was with me for various reasons(closed kita etc.) and never got this kind of (shitty) monologue. 
The question that comes to my mind is, in the technical field (e.g. Pharmaceuticals/chemical industry /Data science /analytics /medtech etc), how do I choose the company or job role to apply to (I wish some flexibility in time and ideally work from home option) ? Should I avoid startups altogether? Also I'm a (wannabe) career changer from academia, for one obvious reason that there's very limited career opportunities for me in academia. I feel quite depressed that my skills sometimes don't matter because I'm a mom. I want some advice from fellow career moms&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Answer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the interviewer brought that as the first question, then clearly it's not a good place to work for.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tech especially is in a privileged place and a lot of people are seeking out people/family/remote-friendly working options.
Regarding career in tech being high pressure: Job pressure is not only limited to the tech domain, in my opinion. And it also depends on the nature of the job itself, teams, etc.
Regarding how would you choose the company or job: My one piece advice here is to start interviewing at a situation where you have nothing to lose. I often find people applying for jobs only when there is the need and end up being stressed, etc. Tech interviews take a lot of time and energy, so be prepared for this. Also consider the interview process itself as a 2 way process where you too can reject if you don't find it to be a good fit about what you want to do, with whom you want to work etc.
More on helping you find the right job itself: Have a goal in mind during your job search about things that matter to you and start mapping these goals with the observations from the interviews. This way it will give you a better idea about where you want to go eventually.
Lastly, you will encounter both good and bad, even at interviews. Don't let today's interview experience put you down.
Should you want to talk more, or need advice etc. feel free to DM me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><category term="Mentoring"></category><category term="advice"></category><category term="career"></category></entry><entry><title>Story telling inspiration</title><link href="https://princiya.com/newblog/story-telling-inspiration.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-08-15T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-08-15T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Princiya Sequeira</name></author><id>tag:princiya.com,2022-08-15:/newblog/story-telling-inspiration.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Lin Clark https://code-cartoons.com/
Maggie Appleton https://maggieappleton.com/drawinginvisibles1
Julia Evans https://wizardzines.com/
Anand from Gramener http://www.s-anand.net/blog/category/visualisation/
Storylabs from Gramener https://gramener.com/storylabs/&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Draft"></category><category term="notes"></category></entry><entry><title>Women Who Code Fellowship 2021 - My experience</title><link href="https://princiya.com/newblog/women-who-code-fellowship-2021-my-experience.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-08-07T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-08-07T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Princiya Sequeira</name></author><id>tag:princiya.com,2022-08-07:/newblog/women-who-code-fellowship-2021-my-experience.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I gave my first keynote at WWCode Connect Recharge 2022. I am humbled by this opportunity. As a leadership fellow with WWCode I get to interact with the community and be recognised as a leader outside of my regular day to day job too. Thank you WWCode!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got featured …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I gave my first keynote at WWCode Connect Recharge 2022. I am humbled by this opportunity. As a leadership fellow with WWCode I get to interact with the community and be recognised as a leader outside of my regular day to day job too. Thank you WWCode!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got featured in Forbes - &lt;a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/alainapercival/2021/12/01/the-wisdom-of-women-leaders-as-they-forge-the-post-pandemic-future/"&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How has having female leadership helped you in your career?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has helped to bring in more women/female easily into the job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What would you tell the women leaders who has impacted your career?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for being there and continuing to be awesome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What traits have you or want to mimic based on other women in leadership?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like being authentic about myself. It is about who I am and being able to bring myself wholly into the job. I encourage others to do the same. Creating this kind of environment where everyone can be authentic about themselves is what I strive for. Empathy is the next important trait I care about. I was once asked “how to empathise with people when you haven’t been in the situation”. During these times I like to take the time to learn more about the situation itself. Listening well helps to empathise in situations when you cannot show direct empathy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What is your personal philosophy about being a great leader?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great leader is about being a good human being first. To define a great leader in one line - “it is to be able to hold the helm when the sea is not calm”. &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Leadership"></category><category term="wwcode"></category></entry><entry><title>Women Who Code Fellowship 2021 - The application phase</title><link href="https://princiya.com/newblog/women-who-code-fellowship-2021-the-application-phase.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-07-07T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-07-07T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Princiya Sequeira</name></author><id>tag:princiya.com,2022-07-07:/newblog/women-who-code-fellowship-2021-the-application-phase.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This was my pitch while applying for the wwcode fellowship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi, My name is Princiya Sequeira. I am from India but now living in Germany. thanks to the job advertisement I found in the Women who code's newsletter 6 years ago which landed me a job here in Berlin. I …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This was my pitch while applying for the wwcode fellowship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi, My name is Princiya Sequeira. I am from India but now living in Germany. thanks to the job advertisement I found in the Women who code's newsletter 6 years ago which landed me a job here in Berlin. I have more than 10 years of experience building full-stack web &amp;amp; mobile applications, and 3 years of experience leading technical teams at scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from my day job, I also volunteer in coaching under-represented folks with opensource contributions, advise them with career decisions, resume reviews, and interview preparations. Given this background, I am very excited to apply for this leadership fellow position because I want to be able to make an impact to a larger global audience. As an underrepresented person in tech myself, I understand the challenges and do believe and strive to have a diverse representation at a technical leadership level at companies and in opensource. I do take pride in being able to be at an engineering management position which I envisioned 10 years ago and to get here I have had to overcome multiple hurdles. It's not an easy road and this is what definitely keeps me motivated, but often there are times when I am alone all by myself and nobody to the immediate rescue. Communities and events like this are a great place where you find similar people with whom you can connect to, get inspired by and to know that you are not alone. It is a matter of time when diverse representation in tech becomes the new norm and we don't have to empower the already empowered under-represented folks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is literally true that we can succeed best and quickest by helping others to learn and succeed and with Women who code events together we can do so much. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Begin by introducing yourself. Tell us why you are interested in becoming a Leadership Fellow.
Next, we want to hear your Women Who Code pitch! Pretend you are starting your first event as a Fellow and share the WWCode Mission, Vision, and Code of Conduct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Planning
Promotion
Agenda&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We want to know how you would plan your first event.This question is required. *
Explain the steps you would follow to plan the event, sharing as much detail as you'd like!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Topic - Theme
Marketing
Speakers
Budget
Feedback
Logistics
Registration
Quality
Code of conduct&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choose a topic. "Craft your own web development journey" - We want to showcase different topics that one can choose to strengthen their web development career path.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find speaker(s), check their availability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Call for speakers from the audience sign up if they have any interesting web development journey to share. Security, accessibility, developer tools, core web standards, performance optimisations, opensource contributions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arrange budget/sponsors: Speaker reimbursements, logistics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setup tools/software for: event registration, volunteer management, feedback collection, notify audience and communicate with them about event updates, moderate the event access and guest list, record the event.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assign volunteers to tasks, event moderation, topic curation, logistics, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write a Code of conduct for the event.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Measure the event's success: Setup metrics to collect, gather feedback from audience and speakers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How would you promote the event?This question is required. *
Consider the timeline, where you would promote it, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Promote the event primarily on social media: Twitter (start promotion asap details are finalised).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write a blog post about the event (2-3 weeks prior)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask speakers, volunteers, audience to promote the event (before and during the event)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Excite the audience who has signed up with additional details about the events, topics, etc. via emails&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identify volunteers to participate in event promotion and track progress. Focus on open and clear communication to meet expectations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Describe the event agendaThis question is required. *
Explain start time, segments, duration, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Craft your own web development journey" - We want to showcase different topics that one can choose to strengthen their web development career path.
- Choose a time slot that best fits global audience.
- Ideally 3-5 hour event with wellness break, community chat time, etc. If there are ample topics and speaker availability then it could also be an 8 hour event.
- If an ideal time slot cannot be found, run the event in 2 batches so that majority of the audience can participate.
- Introduction (15 min)
- Speaker 1 (20 mins, 5 min QnA)
- 5 min break
- Speaker 2 (20 mins, 5 min QnA)
- 10 min break
- Lightning talks (30 mins)
- Break
- Ask me anything or panel discussion (45 mins)
- Game: (blind website design challenge or quiz)
- Wrap up&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q: How has Women Who Code impacted your career and why is it important to you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I gave my first keynote at WWCode Connect Recharge 2022. I am humbled by this opportunity. As a leadership fellow with WWCode I get to interact with the community and be recognised as a leader outside of my regular day to day job too. Thank you WWCode!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q: How will you benefit from this scholarship? Please share 2 professional goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am looking at ways to scale my career to the next level and I believe this scholarship can help me get access to a leadership coach, a global community of other peers who are on a similar path and learn and grow alongside.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Leadership"></category><category term="wwcode"></category></entry><entry><title>3 tips for volunteer management</title><link href="https://princiya.com/newblog/3-tips-for-volunteer-management.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-06-15T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-06-15T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Princiya Sequeira</name></author><id>tag:princiya.com,2022-06-15:/newblog/3-tips-for-volunteer-management.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As a Leadership Fellow at Women Who Code, I talk to many folks interested in volunteering. These folks are either students or full-time job holders. They are usually excited about the prospect, but many fail to balance their time or even find the time and are ultimately unable to uphold …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As a Leadership Fellow at Women Who Code, I talk to many folks interested in volunteering. These folks are either students or full-time job holders. They are usually excited about the prospect, but many fail to balance their time or even find the time and are ultimately unable to uphold their volunteering commitments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below are 3 tips that I often advise the community on how to efficiently manage their time between volunteering and other full-time activities and how to make the most of the community experience while not getting burned out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Move Away from Hustle Culture&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to my observation, people sometimes want to be volunteers because they see others doing it and subscribe to the hustle culture. These people are the ones who often don’t come back when they realize volunteering is not meant for them—and that’s fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Social media is all around us, and it is easy to be influenced by what others are doing. I am not asking people to stop being ambitious, but rather to focus on one’s energy in doing things that truly matter to them. We don't have to do something just because someone else is doing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Prioritize Things That Matter to You&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We don’t have to work on a side project because someone else is working on it or we don’t have to pick up a hobby to read books just for the sake of it. Each one of us is in a unique situation and our timings don’t have to coincide with what is important to other people. A busy week for one person might be an easy week for someone else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is important or what is to be prioritized in this situation is to realize that our brains need to recharge and reset from the hustle and bustle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Learn to Say “No”&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time management is a common topic of my discussions within the community. Some people know and acknowledge they are in a time crisis, but others are shy or hesitant to admit this. In order to have a good time balance, it is important to unlearn saying yes to everything, learn to say “NO,” and learn to prioritize what’s most important for oneself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following is a good checklist to consider when learning to say “No” to new tasks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What purpose does this serve? “Be selfish, and identify what is most important to you” is what I constantly tell the volunteers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does this purpose align with my goals and priorities?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How might this drain my energy or motivation?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How will I refuel?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the phone battery drains it sends us scrambling for our chargers. Similarly, when a given workload drains our batteries, we often tend to ignore our own blinking red battery icon. We need to reevaluate the stereotypes and normalize having lazy weekends by doing nothing or binge-watching our favorite shows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As humans, we need to rest and recharge even more than our devices do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><category term="Leadership"></category><category term="wwcode"></category><category term="priorities"></category><category term="advice"></category></entry><entry><title>My Pitch</title><link href="https://princiya.com/newblog/my-pitch.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-06-04T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-06-04T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Princiya Sequeira</name></author><id>tag:princiya.com,2022-06-04:/newblog/my-pitch.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's been 10 months since I joined Anaconda and I realised I hadn't updated my Linkedin bio or other references to reflect this new job in the description.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I 💙 food and JavaScript! At Anaconda, I am now getting Pythonised!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a skilled programmer with strong communication skills and a …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's been 10 months since I joined Anaconda and I realised I hadn't updated my Linkedin bio or other references to reflect this new job in the description.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I 💙 food and JavaScript! At Anaconda, I am now getting Pythonised!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a skilled programmer with strong communication skills and a dozen years of experience building full-stack web &amp;amp; mobile apps, implementing CI/CD solutions, and supporting infrastructures, including ~5 years of experience leading technical teams at scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TL;DR&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I work as an Engineering Manager at Anaconda. My top strengths are Strategic, Relator, Achiever, Learner, and Responsibility. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also spend my time with the women who code community as a Leadership Fellow on the wwcode frontend technical track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my previous job,  I worked for Curalie GmbH, Berlin as Head of Frontend Engineering. I have been in the web development field for 12+ years. During this tenure, I have had the exposure to deal with full-stack web and mobile app development including dev-ops work, UX tasks, and mentoring team members. I also have exposure to working with IoT, VR/AR, Data visualizations, and Machine Learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been a Software Developer coach at Raise.dev and MLH Fellowship where I coached undergraduates in contributing to opensource, offered them career advice, and prepared them into getting internships or full-time jobs in Software Engineering. Through this program, I mentored open-source contributors to popular open-source repositories like React Native core, AWS Amplify, and Slate.js.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I contribute to open-source and maintain(ed) Lightbeam which is a browser extension to visualize first and third-party trackers. I have also served as a community maintainer for the Firefox dev tools debugger project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been speaking at international conferences since 2015 on web frontend-related topics. I also maintain a blog where I blog about my journey into an engineering leadership role and solving technical problems. https://princiya.com&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before the covid pandemic, I volunteered my time in co-organizing the Berlin critical tech meetup, curating diversity scholarship applications for JSConfEU and React India conferences, and co-hosting the bi-weekly D&amp;amp;I community &amp;amp; contributor calls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have also participated in the mentorship program for the Node.js Diagnostics working group and Open Source Maintainer Leadership program from Mozilla.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skills:
- React, React Native, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, Webpack, Docker, AWS, CI/CD, DevOps, Test automation, Data visualizations, Python
- Empathetic leadership and strong communication
- Strategic, Relator, Achiever, Learner, and Responsibility. 
- Translate tech jargon into meaningful cartoons and mental models&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Bio"></category><category term="resume"></category><category term="pitch"></category></entry><entry><title>Things that made me smile today</title><link href="https://princiya.com/newblog/things-that-made-me-smile-today.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-05-30T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-05-30T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Princiya Sequeira</name></author><id>tag:princiya.com,2022-05-30:/newblog/things-that-made-me-smile-today.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Happy Monday! Yet another Monday, but I had a relaxing day today after a 4 day long weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bonus, it is US holiday today, it is memorial day there and my US colleagues are having a long weekend too. This is also the reason why my day is not too …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Happy Monday! Yet another Monday, but I had a relaxing day today after a 4 day long weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bonus, it is US holiday today, it is memorial day there and my US colleagues are having a long weekend too. This is also the reason why my day is not too packed today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I received the following message on Linkedin today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;I&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;don&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="err"&gt;&amp;#39;t know if you remember me but we were in the same class in the first year of Engg. at NMAMIT i.e., in 2005. I was a Civil Engg. student. I have been following your updates on Twitter and admire your thoughts and community efforts. Great to see you doing well.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This made me smile and made my Monday &amp;lt;3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also went to Savory Chay today, one of my favorite lunch places in Berlin and met a colleague over lunch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The food was delicious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I plan to cook lasagna for dinner today, fingers crossed!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Journal"></category><category term="random"></category></entry><entry><title>What to learn</title><link href="https://princiya.com/newblog/what-to-learn.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-05-29T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-05-29T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Princiya Sequeira</name></author><id>tag:princiya.com,2022-05-29:/newblog/what-to-learn.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today is the end of the 4 day long weekend. I have had a great Sunday so far, and I still have time today to quickly jot down something for a daily blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spend time with the WWCode Frontend technical track community as a Leadership Fellow. During the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today is the end of the 4 day long weekend. I have had a great Sunday so far, and I still have time today to quickly jot down something for a daily blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spend time with the WWCode Frontend technical track community as a Leadership Fellow. During the beginning of this year 2022, I started a bi-weekly series called &lt;a href="https://frontendstudygroup.github.io/blog/tags/what-to-learn"&gt;"What to Learn"&lt;/a&gt; to share ideas to learn new topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was very happy with the outcome and this experiment that took place in Q1 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What to learn - summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I published 6 articles in this series, 3 of which were contributed by the wwcode frontend community. My goal was this to be a community led series and with 2 people coming forward to write 3 posts was a big win for me and goal accomplised for this experiment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, I learned and wrote about &lt;a href="./tag/serverless"&gt;Serverless&lt;/a&gt; and also built a slack integration (aka bot) to bookmark articles shared in wwcode's frontend slack which were then consolidated into a blog post to showcase community's learnings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Writing consistently is not easy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have had many failed attempts in the past to publish content regularly. Given this history I was very cautious with this bi-weekly series and wanted to make sure this is a limited edition (for Q1 2022 only) and not to overwhelm myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were multiple times that I felt after the first month, i.e. after the first 2 posts in January, when I had to write in February I did not find the time, found 2 weeks was too short, and I had to push myself. This is where I encouraged folks from the community to write and was happy when 2 people expressed interest and wrote 3 posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am on the 9th day of my daily writing spree. Fingers crossed that this becomes a daily habit!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How to find new topics to learn&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href="https://princiya.com/blog/how-to-learn/"&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; post I have explained how to learn new topics or how not to give up on the learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there is lot of advice on how to learn, the best way to learn new things is by doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During my time as a mentor for the MLH Fellowship, I met many interesting mentees. One of them was building a Github clone, i.e. his own version of Github and during my conversations with him I learned about &lt;a href="https://github.com/microsoft/monaco-editor"&gt;monaco editor&lt;/a&gt;, the editor that powers VSCode!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a great example to find new topics to learn, i.e. identify topics from the daily things that we use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found &lt;a href="https://github.com/codecrafters-io/build-your-own-x"&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; great resource to build your own version of &lt;code&gt;x&lt;/code&gt; through my colleague during our 1:1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How to find opensource projects to contribute&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, if you want to contribute to opensource, the best way is to look for projects that you use on a daily basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, in the frontend world, look for Typescript's codebase, or even React or React Native's codebase. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or eslint, babel, Jest, etc. All source code is there on Github and is a great way to look into the current issues on these projects and see if you can contribute or fix some &lt;code&gt;good-first-bugs&lt;/code&gt; from these codebases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this is your first time contribution, then these are not recommended, it can be overwhelming. You can search for good first projects for first time opensource contributions and you can find a better list.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Mentoring"></category><category term="learning"></category></entry><entry><title>Leader vs Manager</title><link href="https://princiya.com/newblog/leader-vs-manager.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-05-28T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-05-28T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Princiya Sequeira</name></author><id>tag:princiya.com,2022-05-28:/newblog/leader-vs-manager.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am an Engineering Manager and an Engineering Leader. What is the difference?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This can be an interview question and it is very important to be prepared with a good answer here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was asked this interview question during one of the panel rounds at Anaconda, I really liked …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am an Engineering Manager and an Engineering Leader. What is the difference?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This can be an interview question and it is very important to be prepared with a good answer here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was asked this interview question during one of the panel rounds at Anaconda, I really liked this question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first obvious difference to come to my mind based on my experience is that as a leader I often try to lead by an example. As a manager, I need to ensure that I manage people and project deliverables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Leader&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Manager&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;One who leads&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;One who manages&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Leading by examples and leading from the front&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Manage people and projects&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Influence and motivate the team&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Delegate, orchestrate things within the team&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All leaders are not managers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><category term="Leadership"></category><category term="interview"></category></entry><entry><title>How I spent my holiday</title><link href="https://princiya.com/newblog/how-i-spent-my-holiday.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-05-27T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-05-27T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Princiya Sequeira</name></author><id>tag:princiya.com,2022-05-27:/newblog/how-i-spent-my-holiday.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It is a 4-day long weekend. Yesterday, 26th May was a German public holiday, and today is a snake day holiday from Anaconda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent the entire day yesterday preparing for my &lt;a href="./reset-and-recharge-my-first-keynote"&gt;keynote talk at WWCode Connect 2022&lt;/a&gt;, which was very well received. There was a lot of positive feedback …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It is a 4-day long weekend. Yesterday, 26th May was a German public holiday, and today is a snake day holiday from Anaconda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent the entire day yesterday preparing for my &lt;a href="./reset-and-recharge-my-first-keynote"&gt;keynote talk at WWCode Connect 2022&lt;/a&gt;, which was very well received. There was a lot of positive feedback and appreciation. Personally, I am very happy with this talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Snake days at Anaconda&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Anaconda, we have a snake day holiday every month. In Germany, in addition to the 30 day annual leave, we also get snake day holidays. So we have 30 + 12 days of annual leave at Anaconda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are hiring at Anaconda, do check open roles or contact me if you are interested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What did I do today&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I woke up late and got to my desk only an hour ago. At the time of writing this post, it is 17:04 CET.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been browsing random things, looking at some home office furniture to buy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I watched a little bit of Bling Empire on Netflix earlier today. Riverdale, Bridgerton are on my list. I cannot believe Riverdale has a new season 6!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been following up on social media from yesterday's keynote comments and feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://mailchi.mp/066157bf02bb/connect-forward-is-1-month-away-872086"&gt;following&lt;/a&gt; was sent on today's WWCode newsletter, and I have been cross-posting this on my social media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="WWCode newsletter highlighted my keynote" src="./images/keynote.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;9 months at Anaconda&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I have long weekends, I also sit and think about my career. Today was analysing how are things for me at Anaconda. I have been with Anaconda for 9 months now and things are really good, I am happy about my progress overall and the kind of problems I get to solve on a daily basis. There is so much learning happening everyday and so much work getting done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyday I look forward to growing in my career, one step at a time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;My reading list&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I read a few articles from Leaddev today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am now reading few system design articles from ByteByteGo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was following updates from InvactMetaversity, looks like the drama has been resolved today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Will I have my own startup&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I often think to myself, if I were to build something what would that be? I still have not found any answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do occassionally come up with ideas and think they could be the next big thing. The following were the ones where I came close to get them executed, but did not. Obviously, had I done, it would have already been the next big thing :D. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Portal to connect midwives and new moms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatic blog generator based on the content read or written for that week&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Grow in my career&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I am not sure about a startup, I am definitely aiming to grow in my career and I do believe I am in the right track!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Director &amp;gt; VP &amp;gt; CTO&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><category term="Journal"></category><category term="random"></category></entry><entry><title>Reset and Recharge - my first keynote</title><link href="https://princiya.com/newblog/reset-and-recharge-my-first-keynote.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-05-26T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-05-26T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Princiya Sequeira</name></author><id>tag:princiya.com,2022-05-26:/newblog/reset-and-recharge-my-first-keynote.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Cover image" src="images/reset.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1KiK9KJGHodYgOnMZZs371uKo8FYsw1abgFkH11Tz1a8/edit#slide=id.gf8d3ef5cb9_2_0"&gt;Slides - Reset and Recharge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the phone battery drains, what do we do? When the laptop gets heated up, what do we do? We are forced to shut it down, or buy a replacement in the worst case. In this era, the blinking red battery icons on our smartphones, tablets …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Cover image" src="images/reset.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1KiK9KJGHodYgOnMZZs371uKo8FYsw1abgFkH11Tz1a8/edit#slide=id.gf8d3ef5cb9_2_0"&gt;Slides - Reset and Recharge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the phone battery drains, what do we do? When the laptop gets heated up, what do we do? We are forced to shut it down, or buy a replacement in the worst case. In this era, the blinking red battery icons on our smartphones, tablets and laptops send us all scrambling for our chargers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What do we do&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, when work drains our battery by the middle of the week, what do we do? When the workload increases and our brain can no longer process things, what do we do? Take a moment to realise what do you actually do?
We all have our own reasons to be doing what we have done or what we do,
But, how many times have you ignored the blinking red battery icon on yourself, and pushed yourself hard? If yes, why? What would you have done alternately?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Break the stereotypes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this age of “Just do it” and “Yes we can” , refusal has come to be seen as something negative. “No” is what tired, worn-out people say. “No, stop that” is what sleep-deprived parents tell their energetic children. We need to stop these stereotypes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reset, recharge, reboot, restart - humans need it more than the devices!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Reset from the hustle culture&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this world of social media, it is easy to get tempted to do what others are doing. I am not asking here you all to stop being ambitious but rather to focus on your energy in doing things that truly matter to you.
We don't have to read books or pick up hobbies just because others are doing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Do things that matter to you&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can still have a good weekend by being lazy or just binge-watching. What is important is to be able to take frequent pauses from the busy life, reset oneself, and be recharged!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Volunteering and time management&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a Leadership Fellow at WWCode, I talk to a lot of folks who are interested in volunteering. They are usually excited about the opportunity, and for many, this is their first time volunteering gig. But one of the biggest problems is that many fail to balance their time and end up not coming back to their volunteering commitments.
I try to tell them that they do not have to be guilty if they fail to find time for their volunteering commitments. I ask them to take up tasks that have the maximum benefit for them and not take upon tasks that they are forced to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From my observation, people want to be volunteers sometimes mostly by seeing others doing it, i.e. hustle culture. These are the ones who usually never come back when they realize that this is not meant for them. And that’s fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One important learning here is to be selfish, identify what is important for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Learn to say No&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time management is a common topic during my discussions with the community. The only difference was that some knew and acknowledged they were in a time crisis, but others were shy or hesitated to admit this.
As you start your career or the next step for yourself in life, this is one of the things you will have to unlearn and learn. Unlearn from saying yes to everything, Learn to say NO and learn to prioritise the important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Few questions to ask before saying yes!
What purpose does this serve? Be selfish here, identify what does really matter to you
Let’s say you said yes, it is still not late to say no. What is stealing my energy or motivation? How do I refuel?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Does life get boring&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was once asked by an intern if life as a software developer ever get boring after years of work?
I asked them how did it feel like to be an intern?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Were you bored?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Was it challenging?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Were the days exciting?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Did you think of giving up?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then asked them to  reflect on the thing they did prior to their internship and if there were any similarities.
Life as a software developer too goes through these phases, most of the time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Boring&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Challenging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exciting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;My first failure&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Failures will come along the way; you may not get your desired promotion or it might take a lot of time until you land your first job.
When I graduated in 2009, almost a dozen years ago, there was a global recession and things didn’t go as planned for me. I cried a lot the day after my first failed job interview. Being good at academics and extra curriculars, this was the first biggest failure for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was hopeful that I would make it to the next company but this kept happening couple more times and I had no clue about what was going wrong. I gave up after a few attempts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;I gave up&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I felt like I needed a break after studying all those years so hard and not being able to find my dream job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That year, in 2009, I took up a teaching job and for the next two years I worked as a Lecturer in Computer Science at an engineering college. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unknowingly, I got a recharge in my life. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was happy, some of my colleagues were my best friends, we are still good friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking back at it, If I were to advice my younger self, then I would say that everything happens for good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you aren’t being rejected more than accepted, you’re not asking for enough, reaching high enough and valuing yourself enough. Try new things, do things you are scared of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I quit this teaching job after 2 years, and in 2011 I joined as a full time software engineer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;No risk, no story!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the initial years as a Software Engineer, I worked at a startup, so I had the opportunity to do full-stack, understand BE systems, dev ops, databases, UI design, etc. If I can recollect, it's this learning environment that I had that led me to learn and grow in my career. 
Sometimes I had to do photoshop, sometimes Java, or sometimes think about why our system was down and running slowly. I was also taking basic lessons on machine learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was working at a startup, and a lot of people including my parents were asking me to leave this company and join a bigger firm. But I stuck to it mainly because I realized how much I had to learn. As they say,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No risk, no story!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the career path I wanted, I chose it for myself and I have worked hard for this. Most important: I am very happy today and I continue to love what I do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Reset and recharge - what can we learn from computer science&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WWCode Connect is Dedicated to inspiring you to achieve your career advancement goals, recharge your connections, and continue building your skills!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the world of computer science, where algorithms, design patterns and data structures are considered fundamental, what if we were to reframe our thinking around these concepts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Design Patterns&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is there a design pattern towards shaping our career?
Design patterns are typical solutions to commonly occurring problems in software design. 
Each one of our life is unique given the circumstances that we live in. We can have role models to follow, but in the end often we will realise there is no pattern to copy paste a career based on someone else.
Like a design pattern, the exact order of implementation is up to us to shape our career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Algorithms&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An algorithm defines a clear set of actions that can achieve some goal.
What if we had an algorithm to learn?
Like an algorithm and its implementation, each one of our learning efficiency can vary. We can find ourselves to be caught up in a time or a space constraint.
If your plan does not work, change the plan, change the algorithm, tweak it. have a plan B!  Have a goal in your life, always! Avoid changing the goal itself! But tweak your learning algorithm to be efficient to achieve your learning goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Data Structures&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A data structure is a collection of data values, the relationships among them, and the functions or operations that can be applied to the data.
Our habits are like data structures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s the tiny habits that you will cultivate along the way that will help you shape your career into a successful one. Be honest, trustworthy and be true to yourself and your job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t be guilty if you decide to binge watch Netflix or just get a good sleep and enjoy being lazyful over the weekends. Take breaks, drink water, workout, focus on your health. Health is wealth. Nothing is easy and you need to keep learning and working hard all the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Work hard, but smart!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Breadth vs Depth&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I often get asked this question about how to learn.
While there are loads of tools, technologies and frameworks out there, it is natural to get overwhelmed. How to learn new things at this rate?To know something in depth it takes time, and this is where experience counts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are early on in your career or beginning your career I advice folks to try out various topics before deciding what to focus in depth. Go breadth first before depth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Be curious, ask questions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be curious, ask questions and learn new topics. Think like a child, who is curiously exploring various topics. It is very important to have mentors at this stage who will guide you and show you directions to explore more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like a child who should first learn to crawl before learning to walk, during early years it is also important to focus on the core fundamentals which will serve to be the basis as you advance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you are past the early years phase, it is a good time to focus on niche areas or deep dive into the topics that you were passionate about during your breadth first exploration phase.
Now is a good time to indentify if you want to focus on frontend, backend, fullstack, etc. Learn more about the subject, do more of it, practice more of it to get better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Life is a full stack circle&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you feel you are comfortable on a specific topic, move onto the next one and continue this loop. A child learns to crawl, walk, run, talk. These are the basics. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These core skills are used every walk of life and as we advance we grow wiser. When you reach seniority in your career or subject then you need to pick up something new and start the cycle all over again. 
It is getting a Reset, this time not with default settings, but with customised settings based on where you are for the given time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;It is not easy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If only reset was easy like in devices. Humans have emotions and that’s where it makes it complicated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exactly, a year ago I resigned from my previous job to join at Anaconda. Before Anaconda, I was working at Curalie. I had grown in this role into engineering leadership and I could not have been happier with my career path. But after 3 years, it was also the time for me to move on and look for bigger challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resigning from Curalie was not hard, but it turned out to be emotional, more than I expected. I resigned, submitted my papers and had a loud cry. It is during this time that I realised that I just had a job break up, a job that I enjoyed and had grown as a person and a leader.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had to grieve over it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to use the time to say goodbyes to colleagues and work on a good handover. And before joining Anaconda, I had a nice holiday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is not easy. But we are humans, we need it more, we need it often.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is important to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unlearn from being harsh on yourself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not fear failures, learn your lessons and move on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn to stay happy and Look after your well-being.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you women who code for this keynote opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Talks"></category><category term="career"></category><category term="story"></category><category term="advice"></category><category term="wwcode"></category></entry><entry><title>How does a successful career look like</title><link href="https://princiya.com/newblog/how-does-a-successful-career-look-like.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-05-25T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-05-25T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Princiya Sequeira</name></author><id>tag:princiya.com,2022-05-25:/newblog/how-does-a-successful-career-look-like.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I had to replace my sick colleague today for an interview. As an Engineering Manager I do a lot of interviews as the hiring manager. Today's interview I was in the panel to test the candidate's ability &amp;amp; humility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My last question to this candidate was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does success look like …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I had to replace my sick colleague today for an interview. As an Engineering Manager I do a lot of interviews as the hiring manager. Today's interview I was in the panel to test the candidate's ability &amp;amp; humility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My last question to this candidate was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does success look like for you in your career?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Working with interesting people&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The candidate has a music background. And he said he would answer this question from a musician's point of view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Success to him would be getting to work with more interesting people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a musician, he would like to pair with a person to be able to play the best music and this what he expected out of his career too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Software as gardening&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He said, writing code was like gardening. Things don't go as expected all the times, you need to sow the seeds carefully and wait till it flourishes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You need to prune the weeds --&amp;gt; refactoring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I concluded the interview on the following note:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are bugs in both places! Software &amp;amp; gardening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><category term="Mentoring"></category><category term="career"></category><category term="interview"></category></entry><entry><title>My onboarding experience in a remote world</title><link href="https://princiya.com/newblog/my-onboarding-experience-in-a-remote-world.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-05-24T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-05-24T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Princiya Sequeira</name></author><id>tag:princiya.com,2022-05-24:/newblog/my-onboarding-experience-in-a-remote-world.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Cover image" src="images/onboard.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I joined Anaconda in September 2021. During the pandemic, although I got used to working in a remote work setup, starting a new job in a remote first setup was difficult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The difference&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During my time at Curalie, ~1 year was spent in pandemic and remote setup. Things were direct …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Cover image" src="images/onboard.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I joined Anaconda in September 2021. During the pandemic, although I got used to working in a remote work setup, starting a new job in a remote first setup was difficult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The difference&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During my time at Curalie, ~1 year was spent in pandemic and remote setup. Things were direct and it was a smooth transition, mostly because I knew the team, I knew the product, I knew the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Anaconda, I didn’t know my team, I didn’t know the product, I didn’t know the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onboarding was not only about getting the job done, but it also involved dealing with the online fatigue, and timezone differences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wished to see people and interact with them in real life!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What did I do&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We do have a good 30-6-90 day RAMP plan and I used this as an opportunity to understand my primary priorities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My top priority was getting the EM’s job done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I was new at the company, I also used the time to interact with colleagues on slack, participate in initiatives that were not directly related to my team and get to know other teams and people too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Ask questions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from the remote-first setup, joining Anaconda to me was coming to a Python world from Javascript. Most of the things obvious to folks was not obvious to me. I had to step back often and learn so many new things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I kept asking questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried to phrase answers and be courageous to talk about them so that I could be corrected and learn from the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I drew diagrams to help visualise things better and learn things faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What can be improved&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have great empathy for new hires across Anaconda. For the ones in my team, I let them know that the onboarding process can be overwhelming, and we try to improve this experience one step at a time for the folks joining next. &amp;lt;3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photo by Etienne Boulanger https://unsplash.com/photos/LHtFRAsNWSc&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Leadership"></category><category term="onboarding"></category></entry><entry><title>How do I prepare for a Monday</title><link href="https://princiya.com/newblog/how-do-i-prepare-for-a-monday.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-05-23T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-05-23T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Princiya Sequeira</name></author><id>tag:princiya.com,2022-05-23:/newblog/how-do-i-prepare-for-a-monday.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Cover image" src="./images/monday.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is Monday!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I usally need a lot of warm up time on Monday mornings and get productive on Mondays only towards the second half of the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Monday's yak shaving on Friday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to have a productive Monday, I make sure I have a prioritised list ready on …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Cover image" src="./images/monday.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is Monday!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I usally need a lot of warm up time on Monday mornings and get productive on Mondays only towards the second half of the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Monday's yak shaving on Friday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to have a productive Monday, I make sure I have a prioritised list ready on my desk on Friday evening. This is something I started practising recently, and has been working very well for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the weekend, I make sure I don't do any work related things and start work directly on Monday morning. The prioritised list helps me with relevant context to start the Monday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Analog notes taking&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My note taking method is analog. I jot down notes on pen and paper. My biggest satisfaction over the week is crossing off the todos from my list and tossing the paper into the dustbin. This feels like such a big relief from a mental load point of view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How does it help me&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was wondering if the analog way would help me be productive. In this digital age, should I too not make a digital move? How will I access the information from everywhere?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a good memory, but when dealing with multipel things and constant context switching and interruption driven development, it is only natural that I cannot track each and every thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With my analog notes taking, I make it a point to visit my notes every now and then. I write my important todos in a different paper, while writing the random things as they pop up in another paper. This can be multiple papers for a given day based on the workload. When I revisit my notes every now and then, the frequency I am talking about is atleast twice a week, it helps me refresh my memory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then start writing them over again in a new paper and recategorise and reprioritise. Writing over again and revisiting does help me stay on top of things, and there is very little chance to miss out or forget things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Isn't digital better&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With digital ways, it does help me track notes from outside, when I am not on my work desk. But I have little motivation to revisit my digital todos over and over again and hence things sit idle or unvisited for a long time. During this time, my memory is replaced with other things and I forget.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There might be better digital ways, offcourse I am not debating on that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But my choice is analog notes taking, highlight with colors, revisit and get things done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am very productive, and I can totally recommed this way of doing incase you are looking to find a productive way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy Monday! :) &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Leadership"></category><category term="priorities"></category><category term="time"></category></entry><entry><title>Grieving over a job break up</title><link href="https://princiya.com/newblog/grieving-over-a-job-break-up.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-05-22T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-05-22T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Princiya Sequeira</name></author><id>tag:princiya.com,2022-05-22:/newblog/grieving-over-a-job-break-up.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Cover image" src="images/grief.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's been a year! On this day, last year, I resigned from my previous job where I was the Head of Frontend Engineering at Curalie GmbH for 3 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had grown in this role into engineering leadership and I could not have been happier with my career path. But …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Cover image" src="images/grief.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's been a year! On this day, last year, I resigned from my previous job where I was the Head of Frontend Engineering at Curalie GmbH for 3 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had grown in this role into engineering leadership and I could not have been happier with my career path. But after 3 years, it was also the time for me to move on and look for bigger challenges in an environment where values and culture were more valuable for the organisation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;My time at Curalie&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I joined Curalie as a Senior Frontend Engineer and took up the role as Lead Engineer shortly. During this time, I had a team to manage while also overseeing the product deliverables. I was one of the first 5 engineers in the company when I had joined and at the time when I left, the tech team was about ~50, and the frontend team had grown to ~12 people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was still hands-on coding on that role. On the frontend, our team used React and React Native. My favorite accomplishments:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setting up the entire automated build pipeline for React Native using Fastlane &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setting up automated end to end testing for React using Cypress, including api testing using Pact&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setting up automated end to end - integration testing for React Native using Testproject.io that worked well with our manual QA team&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strategising product deliverables and aligning the entire team with the roadmap&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Empathetic and authentic leadership&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Decision to move on was not hard, but emotional&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resigning from Curalie was not hard, but it turned out to be emotional, more than I expected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I resigned, submitted my papers and had a loud cry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is during this time that I realised that I just had a job break up, a job that I enjoyed and had grown as a person and a leader. I had to grieve over it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I asked the following question in Elpha.com.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear Elpha community,
I handed in my resignation at work today. Although I still have the 3-month notice period and was passively preparing for this resignation, I was not ready for the kind of emotions I am having today.
I cried aloud and now I have this sense of loss although I know something exciting is waiting ahead.
How to deal with this or how to mourn effectively?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got good advice from folks and I decided to use the time to say goodbyes to colleagues and work on a good handover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://elpha.com/posts/kpo019t4/how-to-mourn-after-job-resignation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Interviewing and grieving&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As funny as it apears to me today, on the day I resigned I sent an email to Anaconda saying after the first HR screen I was no longer interested in continuing the inteview process. Jessica, SVP Operations at Anaconda convinced me that I should take the Manager screen interview which was scheduled for the next day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had to grieve and I was not ready for an interview. I was tired and needed a break. But since the interview was already scheduled for the next day I decided to continue the interview process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Manager screen at Anaconda&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had no major expectations from the interview, but just after the interview started and I was talking to Nick, the then VP Engineering, I felt a connection. We also spoke about my resignation, me mourning and also how I was not looking forward to the interview and wanted it to be cancelled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Towards the end of the hour, the call went beyond ~10 mins, and we both were happy about our interview. I wanted to a job at Anaconda and I was looking forward to the next rounds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the next panel rounds, I met amazing people who are now great colleagues. During the final round, I met Kevin, CTO, who is now my Manager at Anaconda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had 30 minutes scheduled, and knowing how busy a CTO would be, I had tried to read up as much as I could about Kevin so that I could ask him good questions in the 5 minutes that I would get after he would be done asking me questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Kevin surprised me and asked if I had any questions in the beginning itself. My homework did pay, and we had a good conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I always listen to myself, always on the watch for any signs that bother me. I give a second chance, but beyond that I treat as warning signs and then believe in taking necessary actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although things were good at Curalie, things became limited for my growth both in terms of salary and impact. I decided to resign.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But mourning over a job was a new experience and it is a thing!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Mentoring"></category><category term="job"></category><category term="story"></category></entry><entry><title>My Career Path</title><link href="https://princiya.com/newblog/my-career-path.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-05-21T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-05-21T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Princiya Sequeira</name></author><id>tag:princiya.com,2022-05-21:/newblog/my-career-path.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Cover image" src="images/career.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My name is Princiya Sequeira and I am an Engineering Manager at Anaconda in Germany.
I am from India and I relocated to Germany 7 years ago.
I have a bachelor’s degree in Computer Science engineering, a dozen years of experience building full-stack web and mobile apps, and leading …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Cover image" src="images/career.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My name is Princiya Sequeira and I am an Engineering Manager at Anaconda in Germany.
I am from India and I relocated to Germany 7 years ago.
I have a bachelor’s degree in Computer Science engineering, a dozen years of experience building full-stack web and mobile apps, and leading technical teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During my initial years as a Software Engineer, I worked at a startup, so I had the opportunity to do full-stack, understand BE systems, dev ops, databases, UI design, etc. If I can recollect, it's this learning environment that I had that led me to learn and grow in my career. Sometimes I had to do photoshop, sometimes Java, or sometimes think about why our system was down and running slowly. I was also taking basic lessons on machine learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One important lesson I learned was that code should not be written for the sake of writing, but we need to understand what we expect to achieve and what we want the machines to respond to.
I was working at a startup, and a lot of people including my parents were asking me to leave this company and join a bigger firm. But I stuck to it mainly because I realized how much I had to learn. As they say,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No risk, no story!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the career path I wanted, I chose it for myself and I have worked hard for this. Most important: I am very happy today and I continue to love what I do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also spend my time with the women who code community as a leadership fellow in the front.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being a woman leader in tech has helped me to bring in more women, and under-represented folks into the tech world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My philosophy about being a great leader is about being a good human being first. I like being authentic about myself. It is about who I am and being able to bring myself wholly into the job. I encourage others to do the same. Creating this kind of environment where everyone can be authentic about themselves is what I strive for. Empathy is the next important trait I care about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I often advise people to chase their dreams. Create a learning curve for yourself, and get it verified by your peers or mentors. Find yourself a mentor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not be afraid to ask questions and make sure whatever you choose for yourself, you are happy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Mentoring"></category><category term="career"></category><category term="story"></category><category term="pitch"></category></entry><entry><title>Hello Pelican!</title><link href="https://princiya.com/newblog/hello-pelican.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-05-20T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-05-20T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Princiya Sequeira</name></author><id>tag:princiya.com,2022-05-20:/newblog/hello-pelican.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Cover image" src="./images/pelican.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finally did it! This is my first attempt to move away from Gatsby, static site generator that I used to write my &lt;a href="https://princiya.com/blog"&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; previously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given that I work at Anaconda, and how everything revolves around Python, I decided to try Pelican.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first encounter with Pelican was when I …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Cover image" src="./images/pelican.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finally did it! This is my first attempt to move away from Gatsby, static site generator that I used to write my &lt;a href="https://princiya.com/blog"&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; previously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given that I work at Anaconda, and how everything revolves around Python, I decided to try Pelican.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first encounter with Pelican was when I worked on engineering.anaconda.com last month and customised CSS there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why no to Gatsby&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gatsby was getting slow, and I knew at some point I had to migrate away from Gatsby. The last post I had published was in January.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier this month, during FOSS Friday at Anaconda (once a month we all work on opensource projects) I decided to write a blog post for Anaconda's blog. I wanted to publish the first version of my draft on my blog, but when I tried to deploy Gatsby, it would not run. After &lt;code&gt;n&lt;/code&gt; no. of efforts, event trying to upgrade to Gatsby v3 and v4, I had no luck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why no to Hashnode&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first choice was Hashnode, I had heard lot of good things about Hashnode and how Hashnode let users customise SEO too. I was able to publish my blog post on Hashnode, and in the excitement I also published 2 additional posts that I was wanting to write.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hashnode was very easy to use and setup. But in the end I wanted to own and be able to customise my blog the way I wanted. I even considered paid options, because in ~6 months time I didn't want to run into the same problem I faced with Gatsby; i.e. either the tech dependencies get outdated and I need to spend time on catching up with the latest versions or some platform like Hashnode ends up restrictions on users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Pelican it is&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past, I have tried Jekyll and Hugo. I was not happy with both of them, mainly because they were not Javascript based. This is the reason, I was very happy in using Gatsby, and to add to my comfort, it was React based. I did get to learn GraphQL too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the comfort zone I was in, I chose to ignore all of Gatsby's warning signs and at the time of writing this blog post I had to finally choose between Hashnode vs Pelican, and I chose Pelican.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Next steps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the last 2 years, I did spend decent time in customising my Gatsby blog; CSS, content and social sharing cards. In fact, I also wrote a custom Gatsby plugin to have automated social sharing cards in GIFs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, I have all the things I need from Pelican. I will focus on writing as a consistent habit and when I get time I will try to migrate my entire blog to this newer version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fingers crossed!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Python"></category><category term="blog"></category><category term="story"></category></entry><entry><title>Resume Review</title><link href="https://princiya.com/newblog/resume-review.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-02-15T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-02-15T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Princiya Sequeira</name></author><id>tag:princiya.com,2022-02-15:/newblog/resume-review.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Cover image" src="images/resume.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resume is your marketing pitch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Following is an excerpt from "RE:View Series - Resume Review" that I organised for WWCode Frontend in February 2022.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good advice I have received is - apply for jobs not when you need them but apply for jobs when you need the least so that …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Cover image" src="images/resume.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resume is your marketing pitch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Following is an excerpt from "RE:View Series - Resume Review" that I organised for WWCode Frontend in February 2022.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good advice I have received is - apply for jobs not when you need them but apply for jobs when you need the least so that you have nothing to lose, can perform well under pressure. So that also applies to make sure you constantly update your resume to know the trends, what works vs what does not. 🙂 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For non-English speakers, would recommend to use a grammar checker. I am not a native speaker myself and always use Grammarly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;+100 to recruiters/hiring managers scan the resume very quickly. Personally, I can scan a resume very quickly and will get an initial impression less than 10 seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recommend .pdf resumes but with working hyperlinks if you include them. .doc or other formats can corrupt when you upload/share.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any guidance on what should go first, experience or education?
Me to Everyone (18:27)
Relevant experience would be better. Since education although important these days we give value to project work and experience.
C S to Host and Panelists (18:27)
Question. For skill section, should we include html, css, and javascript? Or if I say React and taiwind(or any css frameworks) is just fine?
Jiaqi to Everyone (18:28)
Hi all! By default chat is set to send to &lt;code&gt;Host and Panelists&lt;/code&gt; only. If you’d like your questions or comments to be viewed by everyone you can switch the To: field to &lt;code&gt;Everyone&lt;/code&gt;
C S to Host and Panelists (18:28)
got it
Me to Everyone (18:28)
For general skills: better to keep it generic - html, css, JS. For project specific mention in depth about react, tailwind etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi, what if internship project was developed in php and we want to apply for other tech then can we keep it in resume?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 page vs 2
write bullet points
write what you are comfortable with
grammar checks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the internship project was not deployed due to some issue, still we can put it right?
Yes sure. Internship projects are still useful. If this is your first real job or another internship application, then as long as you have lessons learned from your project, put it down. For juniors being able to show and demonstrate your learning curve is very important&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;what if the unrelated job experience is your current employer and you only point out collaboration, problem solving, and adaptability bullets?
assuming you will switch jobs. then it is ok to list unrelated job experience as a brief summary. and be able to show anything relevant experience/projects to the job you are applying itself would be good&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, Can you please tell if someone wants to switch career from full stack developer to Data scientist, then what to put in resume? All work related to full stack wont help much right? or we should wait and do some data science projects and then switch?
For example, let’s say you have been a full stack for a few years. Now you want to switch to data scientist. If you switch within your existing company you have higher chances since they know you and your work already. Externally if you apply for a different job then you will have to prove yourself how can you navigate through the role. so sometimes high chances you will be considered junior there. Makes sense?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How closely does the resume need to match your LinkedIn profile, structure-wise and wording… esp if we’re building more than one resume (i.e., to, say, apply for 2 different jobs)
Jiaqi to Everyone (18:55)
It doesn’t need to match. But having a strong LinkedIn profile makes you more discoverable. There’s different strategies there.
Jana Panarites to Everyone (18:55)
Thanks Jiaqu!
Jiaqi  :-/
C S to Everyone (18:56)
very helpful critiques! thank you so much
Jiaqi to Everyone (18:56)
By more discoverable, I mean if you have a strong LinkedIn profile, recruiters and Hiring Managers will come to you and reach out to you for relevant roles.
Stephanie Rideout to Everyone (18:56)
Your LinkedIn profile is an excellent space to include additional information, such as extra portfolio links, participation in hackathons, volunteer commitments, etc.
Me to Everyone (18:56)
+1 to what Jiaqi says. It doesn’t have to match. But the overall gist of your message that you want to tell via resume needs to be consistent. Or would be nice that you are consistent 🙂&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I'm transitioning into tech, how much previous non-tech experience should go on the resume?
non-tech experience would not matter. so keep it short and brief. try to highlight your learnings&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Men apply for jobs where they have 60% of the “required skills” posted; women apply only when they have 100%.  I’ve learned that as women, we must get over it and APPLY APPLY APPLY&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;normalise taking career break!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi! I have a question about obtaining metrics for a resume, ex. "Increased user efficiency by 30%.....", "reduced compile time by 15%", etc. I often hear an emphasis to include numbers and data concerning your responsibilities at a job to make it sound more concrete, but I was always curious as to how you can get these!? Do you talk to your engineering manager, tech lead, or is this something you estimate/calculate yourself?
I mean in all seriousness, those are best guess metrics. You can talk to your EM or Tech Lead but they’ll probably have to guesstimate too. If you have a healthy relationship with your co-workers, you can get their perspective.
But generally if you own a project, own an initiative, you are the best qualified person to measure success metrics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://thetechresume.com/table-of-contents.html&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Mentoring"></category><category term="career"></category><category term="job"></category><category term="resume"></category></entry><entry><title>Stateful Serverless</title><link href="https://princiya.com/newblog/stateful-serverless.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-01-16T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-01-16T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Princiya Sequeira</name></author><id>tag:princiya.com,2022-01-16:/newblog/stateful-serverless.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href="./serverless-react"&gt;part 1&lt;/a&gt; of this post I created a React application, deployed on Netlify which had serverless functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Usecase - collect links to share with the community&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like I mentioned above, I want to share topics to learn with the community. With this React application, I want to collect links …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href="./serverless-react"&gt;part 1&lt;/a&gt; of this post I created a React application, deployed on Netlify which had serverless functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Usecase - collect links to share with the community&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like I mentioned above, I want to share topics to learn with the community. With this React application, I want to collect links, which is the first step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a next step, I want to tag the articles and group them by date. Once the data model is setup about how to tag and group by date, this needs to be stored in a database. The reason why I could not complete the 19 minute course in 19 minutes is that I got distracted with all the ideas and how I could shape this simple serverless application into a sophiscated bot to generate weekly curated learning lists tagged by topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope to work further on this serverless application and blog about it. Stay tuned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Overview of databases for serverless functions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://vercel.com/docs/concepts/solutions/databases#providers"&gt;This&lt;/a&gt; is a good list of database providers which work well with serverless functions. If you look into the list, I have used MongoDB, PostgreSQL, AWS Dynamo DB, MySQL, AWS S3 in the past. Since the egghead.io course application was about deploying using Netlify, I quickly looked into FaunaDB. I also read about Supabase because I remember hearing about it on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also took this time to learn little bit about Hasura because I had heard a lot about Hasura recently. Hasura offers a GraphQL engine and we can write GraphQL APIs on supported databases like PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I was reading more, I came across KeystoneJS and read little bit on that. KeysteonJS offers CMS capabilities and GraphQL API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is definitely lots going on GraphQL and JAMstack side of things. I was amazed and overwhelmed about how easy it is these days to give extra wings to frontend developers by being able to deploy the work with little hassle with serverless powered applications.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Technical"></category><category term="serverless"></category></entry><entry><title>Serverless React</title><link href="https://princiya.com/newblog/serverless-react.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-01-04T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-01-04T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Princiya Sequeira</name></author><id>tag:princiya.com,2022-01-04:/newblog/serverless-react.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Serverless React application deployed using Netlify, and an overview of databases to make serverless&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New year, new goals! Happy 2022. I have compiled a learning list for myself and one of the topics is to build apps so that I can still stay technical while managing and leading teams. I …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Serverless React application deployed using Netlify, and an overview of databases to make serverless&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New year, new goals! Happy 2022. I have compiled a learning list for myself and one of the topics is to build apps so that I can still stay technical while managing and leading teams. I also want to get into a consistent writing habit, so hopefully this will give me a chance to write and share my learnings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the year end holidays I was looking at the things that could be automated for my WWCode Frontend Fellow's tasks. One thing that I want to do is share topics to learn for middle level and beyond frontend/fullstack developers. I came across Jason Lengstorf's egghead.io course on creating a TypeScript powered &lt;a href="https://egghead.io/lessons/netlify-deploy-a-vite-project-with-the-netlify-cli"&gt;Serverless React application&lt;/a&gt;. I wanted to try this out because it was only 19 minutes long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The course material was very straight forward and I could get a Serverless function on Netlify in no time. Althouth the course was only 19 minutes long, I must admit I got distracted so many times, that it took me more than 8 hours to deploy and have it running &lt;a href="https://eloquent-hamilton-c815fe.netlify.app/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="https://github.com/princiya/serverless"&gt;Here's&lt;/a&gt; the Github repository which is connected to Netlify and the serverless application is deployed. All the steps are explained in the egghead.io course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Usecase - collect links to share with the community&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like I mentioned above, I want to share topics to learn with the community. With this React application, I want to collect links, which is the first step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a next step, I want to tag the articles and group them by date. Once the data model is setup about how to tag and group by date, this needs to be stored in a database. The reason why I could not complete the 19 minute course in 19 minutes is that I got distracted with all the ideas and how I could shape this simple serverless application into a sophiscated bot to generate weekly curated learning lists tagged by topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope to work further on this serverless application and blog about it. Stay tuned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Overview of databases for serverless functions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://vercel.com/docs/concepts/solutions/databases#providers"&gt;This&lt;/a&gt; is a good list of database providers which work well with serverless functions. If you look into the list, I have used MongoDB, PostgreSQL, AWS Dynamo DB, MySQL, AWS S3 in the past. Since the egghead.io course application was about deploying using Netlify, I quickly looked into FaunaDB. I also read about Supabase because I remember hearing about it on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also took this time to learn little bit about Hasura because I had heard a lot about Hasura recently. Hasura offers a GraphQL engine and we can write GraphQL APIs on supported databases like PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I was reading more, I came across KeystoneJS and read little bit on that. KeysteonJS offers CMS capabilities and GraphQL API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is definitely lots going on GraphQL and JAMstack side of things. I was amazed and overwhelmed about how easy it is these days to give extra wings to frontend developers by being able to deploy the work with little hassle with serverless powered applications.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Technical"></category><category term="serverless"></category></entry></feed>