<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>P's blog - Bio</title><link href="https://princiya.com/newblog/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://princiya.com/newblog/feeds/bio.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://princiya.com/newblog/</id><updated>2022-06-04T00:00:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>My Pitch</title><link href="https://princiya.com/newblog/my-pitch.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-06-04T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-06-04T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Princiya Sequeira</name></author><id>tag:princiya.com,2022-06-04:/newblog/my-pitch.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's been 10 months since I joined Anaconda and I realised I hadn't updated my Linkedin bio or other references to reflect this new job in the description.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I 💙 food and JavaScript! At Anaconda, I am now getting Pythonised!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a skilled programmer with strong communication skills and a …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's been 10 months since I joined Anaconda and I realised I hadn't updated my Linkedin bio or other references to reflect this new job in the description.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I 💙 food and JavaScript! At Anaconda, I am now getting Pythonised!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a skilled programmer with strong communication skills and a dozen years of experience building full-stack web &amp;amp; mobile apps, implementing CI/CD solutions, and supporting infrastructures, including ~5 years of experience leading technical teams at scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TL;DR&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I work as an Engineering Manager at Anaconda. My top strengths are Strategic, Relator, Achiever, Learner, and Responsibility. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also spend my time with the women who code community as a Leadership Fellow on the wwcode frontend technical track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my previous job,  I worked for Curalie GmbH, Berlin as Head of Frontend Engineering. I have been in the web development field for 12+ years. During this tenure, I have had the exposure to deal with full-stack web and mobile app development including dev-ops work, UX tasks, and mentoring team members. I also have exposure to working with IoT, VR/AR, Data visualizations, and Machine Learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been a Software Developer coach at Raise.dev and MLH Fellowship where I coached undergraduates in contributing to opensource, offered them career advice, and prepared them into getting internships or full-time jobs in Software Engineering. Through this program, I mentored open-source contributors to popular open-source repositories like React Native core, AWS Amplify, and Slate.js.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I contribute to open-source and maintain(ed) Lightbeam which is a browser extension to visualize first and third-party trackers. I have also served as a community maintainer for the Firefox dev tools debugger project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been speaking at international conferences since 2015 on web frontend-related topics. I also maintain a blog where I blog about my journey into an engineering leadership role and solving technical problems. https://princiya.com&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before the covid pandemic, I volunteered my time in co-organizing the Berlin critical tech meetup, curating diversity scholarship applications for JSConfEU and React India conferences, and co-hosting the bi-weekly D&amp;amp;I community &amp;amp; contributor calls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have also participated in the mentorship program for the Node.js Diagnostics working group and Open Source Maintainer Leadership program from Mozilla.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skills:
- React, React Native, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, Webpack, Docker, AWS, CI/CD, DevOps, Test automation, Data visualizations, Python
- Empathetic leadership and strong communication
- Strategic, Relator, Achiever, Learner, and Responsibility. 
- Translate tech jargon into meaningful cartoons and mental models&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Bio"></category><category term="resume"></category><category term="pitch"></category></entry></feed>