<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>P's blog - Journal</title><link href="https://princiya.com/newblog/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://princiya.com/newblog/feeds/journal.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://princiya.com/newblog/</id><updated>2022-05-27T00:00:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>How I spent my holiday</title><link href="https://princiya.com/newblog/how-i-spent-my-holiday.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-05-27T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-05-27T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Princiya Sequeira</name></author><id>tag:princiya.com,2022-05-27:/newblog/how-i-spent-my-holiday.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It is a 4-day long weekend. Yesterday, 26th May was a German public holiday, and today is a snake day holiday from Anaconda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent the entire day yesterday preparing for my &lt;a href="./reset-and-recharge-my-first-keynote"&gt;keynote talk at WWCode Connect 2022&lt;/a&gt;, which was very well received. There was a lot of positive feedback …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It is a 4-day long weekend. Yesterday, 26th May was a German public holiday, and today is a snake day holiday from Anaconda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent the entire day yesterday preparing for my &lt;a href="./reset-and-recharge-my-first-keynote"&gt;keynote talk at WWCode Connect 2022&lt;/a&gt;, which was very well received. There was a lot of positive feedback and appreciation. Personally, I am very happy with this talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Snake days at Anaconda&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Anaconda, we have a snake day holiday every month. In Germany, in addition to the 30 day annual leave, we also get snake day holidays. So we have 30 + 12 days of annual leave at Anaconda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are hiring at Anaconda, do check open roles or contact me if you are interested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What did I do today&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I woke up late and got to my desk only an hour ago. At the time of writing this post, it is 17:04 CET.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been browsing random things, looking at some home office furniture to buy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I watched a little bit of Bling Empire on Netflix earlier today. Riverdale, Bridgerton are on my list. I cannot believe Riverdale has a new season 6!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been following up on social media from yesterday's keynote comments and feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://mailchi.mp/066157bf02bb/connect-forward-is-1-month-away-872086"&gt;following&lt;/a&gt; was sent on today's WWCode newsletter, and I have been cross-posting this on my social media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="WWCode newsletter highlighted my keynote" src="./images/keynote.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;9 months at Anaconda&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I have long weekends, I also sit and think about my career. Today was analysing how are things for me at Anaconda. I have been with Anaconda for 9 months now and things are really good, I am happy about my progress overall and the kind of problems I get to solve on a daily basis. There is so much learning happening everyday and so much work getting done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyday I look forward to growing in my career, one step at a time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;My reading list&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I read a few articles from Leaddev today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am now reading few system design articles from ByteByteGo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was following updates from InvactMetaversity, looks like the drama has been resolved today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Will I have my own startup&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I often think to myself, if I were to build something what would that be? I still have not found any answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do occassionally come up with ideas and think they could be the next big thing. The following were the ones where I came close to get them executed, but did not. Obviously, had I done, it would have already been the next big thing :D. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Portal to connect midwives and new moms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatic blog generator based on the content read or written for that week&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Grow in my career&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I am not sure about a startup, I am definitely aiming to grow in my career and I do believe I am in the right track!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Director &amp;gt; VP &amp;gt; CTO&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><category term="Journal"></category><category term="random"></category></entry></feed>