<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>P's blog - Leadership</title><link href="https://princiya.com/newblog/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://princiya.com/newblog/feeds/leadership.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://princiya.com/newblog/</id><updated>2023-03-12T00:00:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>Autonomy - How do you manage this on your teams?</title><link href="https://princiya.com/newblog/autonomy-how-do-you-manage-this-on-your-teams.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-03-12T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-03-12T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Princiya Sequeira</name></author><id>tag:princiya.com,2023-03-12:/newblog/autonomy-how-do-you-manage-this-on-your-teams.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;An Engineering Manager peer recently asked this question:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word of the day is: "Autonomy". How do you manage this on your teams? What are is limits (are there any) and what do you do if there is a bigger change the team covers up with you don't agree with …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;An Engineering Manager peer recently asked this question:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word of the day is: "Autonomy". How do you manage this on your teams? What are is limits (are there any) and what do you do if there is a bigger change the team covers up with you don't agree with or are concerned about? This is technology, process, etc.
What do you consider your job or role is around that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was my answer:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enabling my team to have the right level of autonomy is what i consider to be primary of my job role. We would define this via team working agreements, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If there's a bigger change, then this calls for discussions and level setting. HOW this is done, might be unique based on the given situation. but overall, I would make sure I am aligned with the team on our joint definition of autonomy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, I consider accountable to this, so i would work closely with the team in aligning expectations around this.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Leadership"></category><category term="autonomy"></category></entry><entry><title>My Leadership Strengths</title><link href="https://princiya.com/newblog/my-leadership-strengths.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-11-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-11-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Princiya Sequeira</name></author><id>tag:princiya.com,2022-11-01:/newblog/my-leadership-strengths.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My Top 5 Themes
1. Strategic
2. Relator
3. Achiever
4. Learner
5. Responsibility&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Strategic&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People who are especially talented in the Strategic theme create alternative ways to proceed. Faced with any given scenario, they can quickly spot the relevant patterns and issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I too indentify being strategic is one …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My Top 5 Themes
1. Strategic
2. Relator
3. Achiever
4. Learner
5. Responsibility&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Strategic&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People who are especially talented in the Strategic theme create alternative ways to proceed. Faced with any given scenario, they can quickly spot the relevant patterns and issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I too indentify being strategic is one of my biggest strengths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://www.lenareinhard.com/articles/how-to-lead-strategically-every-day&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Relator&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People who are especially talented in the Relator theme enjoy close relationships with others. They find deep satisfaction in working hard with friends to achieve a goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Achiever&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People who are especially talented in the Achiever theme have a great deal of stamina and work hard. They take great satisfaction from being busy and productive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Learner&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People who are especially talented in the Learner theme have a great desire to learn and want to continuously improve. In particular, the process of learning, rather than the outcome, excites them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Responsibility&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People who are especially talented in the Responsibility theme take psychological ownership of what they say they will do. They are committed to stable values such as honesty and loyalty.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Leadership"></category><category term="notes"></category></entry><entry><title>What is the EM aka Engineering Manager role?</title><link href="https://princiya.com/newblog/what-is-the-em-aka-engineering-manager-role.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-09-15T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-09-15T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Princiya Sequeira</name></author><id>tag:princiya.com,2022-09-15:/newblog/what-is-the-em-aka-engineering-manager-role.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The following can be summarized as getting things done and the supporting activities that enable a high performing team environment:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Business Impact - Clear business metrics and working towards ambitious goals &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Team Health - Team members are engaged and complement each other in achieving common goals autonomously &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Productivity - MVP mindset, continuous improvements …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The following can be summarized as getting things done and the supporting activities that enable a high performing team environment:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Business Impact - Clear business metrics and working towards ambitious goals &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Team Health - Team members are engaged and complement each other in achieving common goals autonomously &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Productivity - MVP mindset, continuous improvements of team ways of working &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Systems Health - Defining and delivering towards clear metrics and SLOs &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stakeholder Happiness - Managing dependencies and expectations, building trust with all stakeholders and delivering on commitments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Product, tech and strategy:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Excellent execution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Product partnership&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Impact outside your team&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Influence the roadmap&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be comfortable with uncertainty&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grow a successor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deliver business impact&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Core skills for engineering leadership:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developing teams&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People leadership&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Building culture&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hiring and staffing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tackling difficult conversations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remedying underperformance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Personal development&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Managing up and influencing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Managing across peers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Managing below&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Technical&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tech acumen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to deliver&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Business impact&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a manager and leader, you’ll coach and develop the team, providing regular feedback, and helping each individual to learn, grow and develop their career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ll work closely with product managers, design, and engineers to influence product direction, always keeping quality and the experience of developers top-of-mind with a relentless focus on excellence in user experience. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ll help shape an environment of psychological safety which values experimentation and continuous learning. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ll influence and provide feedback on the organizational culture and processes, always looking for opportunities to improve in a continuous pursuit for excellence.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Leadership"></category><category term="EM"></category></entry><entry><title>Women Who Code Fellowship 2021 - My experience</title><link href="https://princiya.com/newblog/women-who-code-fellowship-2021-my-experience.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-08-07T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-08-07T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Princiya Sequeira</name></author><id>tag:princiya.com,2022-08-07:/newblog/women-who-code-fellowship-2021-my-experience.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I gave my first keynote at WWCode Connect Recharge 2022. I am humbled by this opportunity. As a leadership fellow with WWCode I get to interact with the community and be recognised as a leader outside of my regular day to day job too. Thank you WWCode!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got featured …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I gave my first keynote at WWCode Connect Recharge 2022. I am humbled by this opportunity. As a leadership fellow with WWCode I get to interact with the community and be recognised as a leader outside of my regular day to day job too. Thank you WWCode!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got featured in Forbes - &lt;a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/alainapercival/2021/12/01/the-wisdom-of-women-leaders-as-they-forge-the-post-pandemic-future/"&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How has having female leadership helped you in your career?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has helped to bring in more women/female easily into the job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What would you tell the women leaders who has impacted your career?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for being there and continuing to be awesome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What traits have you or want to mimic based on other women in leadership?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like being authentic about myself. It is about who I am and being able to bring myself wholly into the job. I encourage others to do the same. Creating this kind of environment where everyone can be authentic about themselves is what I strive for. Empathy is the next important trait I care about. I was once asked “how to empathise with people when you haven’t been in the situation”. During these times I like to take the time to learn more about the situation itself. Listening well helps to empathise in situations when you cannot show direct empathy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What is your personal philosophy about being a great leader?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great leader is about being a good human being first. To define a great leader in one line - “it is to be able to hold the helm when the sea is not calm”. &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Leadership"></category><category term="wwcode"></category></entry><entry><title>Women Who Code Fellowship 2021 - The application phase</title><link href="https://princiya.com/newblog/women-who-code-fellowship-2021-the-application-phase.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-07-07T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-07-07T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Princiya Sequeira</name></author><id>tag:princiya.com,2022-07-07:/newblog/women-who-code-fellowship-2021-the-application-phase.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This was my pitch while applying for the wwcode fellowship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi, My name is Princiya Sequeira. I am from India but now living in Germany. thanks to the job advertisement I found in the Women who code's newsletter 6 years ago which landed me a job here in Berlin. I …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This was my pitch while applying for the wwcode fellowship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi, My name is Princiya Sequeira. I am from India but now living in Germany. thanks to the job advertisement I found in the Women who code's newsletter 6 years ago which landed me a job here in Berlin. I have more than 10 years of experience building full-stack web &amp;amp; mobile applications, and 3 years of experience leading technical teams at scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from my day job, I also volunteer in coaching under-represented folks with opensource contributions, advise them with career decisions, resume reviews, and interview preparations. Given this background, I am very excited to apply for this leadership fellow position because I want to be able to make an impact to a larger global audience. As an underrepresented person in tech myself, I understand the challenges and do believe and strive to have a diverse representation at a technical leadership level at companies and in opensource. I do take pride in being able to be at an engineering management position which I envisioned 10 years ago and to get here I have had to overcome multiple hurdles. It's not an easy road and this is what definitely keeps me motivated, but often there are times when I am alone all by myself and nobody to the immediate rescue. Communities and events like this are a great place where you find similar people with whom you can connect to, get inspired by and to know that you are not alone. It is a matter of time when diverse representation in tech becomes the new norm and we don't have to empower the already empowered under-represented folks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is literally true that we can succeed best and quickest by helping others to learn and succeed and with Women who code events together we can do so much. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Begin by introducing yourself. Tell us why you are interested in becoming a Leadership Fellow.
Next, we want to hear your Women Who Code pitch! Pretend you are starting your first event as a Fellow and share the WWCode Mission, Vision, and Code of Conduct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Planning
Promotion
Agenda&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We want to know how you would plan your first event.This question is required. *
Explain the steps you would follow to plan the event, sharing as much detail as you'd like!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Topic - Theme
Marketing
Speakers
Budget
Feedback
Logistics
Registration
Quality
Code of conduct&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choose a topic. "Craft your own web development journey" - We want to showcase different topics that one can choose to strengthen their web development career path.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find speaker(s), check their availability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Call for speakers from the audience sign up if they have any interesting web development journey to share. Security, accessibility, developer tools, core web standards, performance optimisations, opensource contributions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arrange budget/sponsors: Speaker reimbursements, logistics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setup tools/software for: event registration, volunteer management, feedback collection, notify audience and communicate with them about event updates, moderate the event access and guest list, record the event.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assign volunteers to tasks, event moderation, topic curation, logistics, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write a Code of conduct for the event.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Measure the event's success: Setup metrics to collect, gather feedback from audience and speakers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How would you promote the event?This question is required. *
Consider the timeline, where you would promote it, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Promote the event primarily on social media: Twitter (start promotion asap details are finalised).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write a blog post about the event (2-3 weeks prior)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask speakers, volunteers, audience to promote the event (before and during the event)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Excite the audience who has signed up with additional details about the events, topics, etc. via emails&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identify volunteers to participate in event promotion and track progress. Focus on open and clear communication to meet expectations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Describe the event agendaThis question is required. *
Explain start time, segments, duration, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Craft your own web development journey" - We want to showcase different topics that one can choose to strengthen their web development career path.
- Choose a time slot that best fits global audience.
- Ideally 3-5 hour event with wellness break, community chat time, etc. If there are ample topics and speaker availability then it could also be an 8 hour event.
- If an ideal time slot cannot be found, run the event in 2 batches so that majority of the audience can participate.
- Introduction (15 min)
- Speaker 1 (20 mins, 5 min QnA)
- 5 min break
- Speaker 2 (20 mins, 5 min QnA)
- 10 min break
- Lightning talks (30 mins)
- Break
- Ask me anything or panel discussion (45 mins)
- Game: (blind website design challenge or quiz)
- Wrap up&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q: How has Women Who Code impacted your career and why is it important to you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I gave my first keynote at WWCode Connect Recharge 2022. I am humbled by this opportunity. As a leadership fellow with WWCode I get to interact with the community and be recognised as a leader outside of my regular day to day job too. Thank you WWCode!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q: How will you benefit from this scholarship? Please share 2 professional goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am looking at ways to scale my career to the next level and I believe this scholarship can help me get access to a leadership coach, a global community of other peers who are on a similar path and learn and grow alongside.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Leadership"></category><category term="wwcode"></category></entry><entry><title>3 tips for volunteer management</title><link href="https://princiya.com/newblog/3-tips-for-volunteer-management.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-06-15T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-06-15T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Princiya Sequeira</name></author><id>tag:princiya.com,2022-06-15:/newblog/3-tips-for-volunteer-management.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As a Leadership Fellow at Women Who Code, I talk to many folks interested in volunteering. These folks are either students or full-time job holders. They are usually excited about the prospect, but many fail to balance their time or even find the time and are ultimately unable to uphold …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As a Leadership Fellow at Women Who Code, I talk to many folks interested in volunteering. These folks are either students or full-time job holders. They are usually excited about the prospect, but many fail to balance their time or even find the time and are ultimately unable to uphold their volunteering commitments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below are 3 tips that I often advise the community on how to efficiently manage their time between volunteering and other full-time activities and how to make the most of the community experience while not getting burned out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Move Away from Hustle Culture&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to my observation, people sometimes want to be volunteers because they see others doing it and subscribe to the hustle culture. These people are the ones who often don’t come back when they realize volunteering is not meant for them—and that’s fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Social media is all around us, and it is easy to be influenced by what others are doing. I am not asking people to stop being ambitious, but rather to focus on one’s energy in doing things that truly matter to them. We don't have to do something just because someone else is doing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Prioritize Things That Matter to You&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We don’t have to work on a side project because someone else is working on it or we don’t have to pick up a hobby to read books just for the sake of it. Each one of us is in a unique situation and our timings don’t have to coincide with what is important to other people. A busy week for one person might be an easy week for someone else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is important or what is to be prioritized in this situation is to realize that our brains need to recharge and reset from the hustle and bustle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Learn to Say “No”&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time management is a common topic of my discussions within the community. Some people know and acknowledge they are in a time crisis, but others are shy or hesitant to admit this. In order to have a good time balance, it is important to unlearn saying yes to everything, learn to say “NO,” and learn to prioritize what’s most important for oneself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following is a good checklist to consider when learning to say “No” to new tasks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What purpose does this serve? “Be selfish, and identify what is most important to you” is what I constantly tell the volunteers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does this purpose align with my goals and priorities?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How might this drain my energy or motivation?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How will I refuel?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the phone battery drains it sends us scrambling for our chargers. Similarly, when a given workload drains our batteries, we often tend to ignore our own blinking red battery icon. We need to reevaluate the stereotypes and normalize having lazy weekends by doing nothing or binge-watching our favorite shows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As humans, we need to rest and recharge even more than our devices do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><category term="Leadership"></category><category term="wwcode"></category><category term="priorities"></category><category term="advice"></category></entry><entry><title>Leader vs Manager</title><link href="https://princiya.com/newblog/leader-vs-manager.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-05-28T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-05-28T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Princiya Sequeira</name></author><id>tag:princiya.com,2022-05-28:/newblog/leader-vs-manager.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am an Engineering Manager and an Engineering Leader. What is the difference?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This can be an interview question and it is very important to be prepared with a good answer here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was asked this interview question during one of the panel rounds at Anaconda, I really liked …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am an Engineering Manager and an Engineering Leader. What is the difference?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This can be an interview question and it is very important to be prepared with a good answer here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was asked this interview question during one of the panel rounds at Anaconda, I really liked this question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first obvious difference to come to my mind based on my experience is that as a leader I often try to lead by an example. As a manager, I need to ensure that I manage people and project deliverables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Leader&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Manager&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;One who leads&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;One who manages&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Leading by examples and leading from the front&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Manage people and projects&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Influence and motivate the team&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Delegate, orchestrate things within the team&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All leaders are not managers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><category term="Leadership"></category><category term="interview"></category></entry><entry><title>My onboarding experience in a remote world</title><link href="https://princiya.com/newblog/my-onboarding-experience-in-a-remote-world.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-05-24T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-05-24T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Princiya Sequeira</name></author><id>tag:princiya.com,2022-05-24:/newblog/my-onboarding-experience-in-a-remote-world.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Cover image" src="images/onboard.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I joined Anaconda in September 2021. During the pandemic, although I got used to working in a remote work setup, starting a new job in a remote first setup was difficult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The difference&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During my time at Curalie, ~1 year was spent in pandemic and remote setup. Things were direct …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Cover image" src="images/onboard.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I joined Anaconda in September 2021. During the pandemic, although I got used to working in a remote work setup, starting a new job in a remote first setup was difficult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The difference&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During my time at Curalie, ~1 year was spent in pandemic and remote setup. Things were direct and it was a smooth transition, mostly because I knew the team, I knew the product, I knew the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Anaconda, I didn’t know my team, I didn’t know the product, I didn’t know the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onboarding was not only about getting the job done, but it also involved dealing with the online fatigue, and timezone differences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wished to see people and interact with them in real life!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What did I do&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We do have a good 30-6-90 day RAMP plan and I used this as an opportunity to understand my primary priorities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My top priority was getting the EM’s job done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I was new at the company, I also used the time to interact with colleagues on slack, participate in initiatives that were not directly related to my team and get to know other teams and people too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Ask questions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from the remote-first setup, joining Anaconda to me was coming to a Python world from Javascript. Most of the things obvious to folks was not obvious to me. I had to step back often and learn so many new things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I kept asking questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried to phrase answers and be courageous to talk about them so that I could be corrected and learn from the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I drew diagrams to help visualise things better and learn things faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What can be improved&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have great empathy for new hires across Anaconda. For the ones in my team, I let them know that the onboarding process can be overwhelming, and we try to improve this experience one step at a time for the folks joining next. &amp;lt;3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photo by Etienne Boulanger https://unsplash.com/photos/LHtFRAsNWSc&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Leadership"></category><category term="onboarding"></category></entry><entry><title>How do I prepare for a Monday</title><link href="https://princiya.com/newblog/how-do-i-prepare-for-a-monday.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-05-23T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-05-23T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Princiya Sequeira</name></author><id>tag:princiya.com,2022-05-23:/newblog/how-do-i-prepare-for-a-monday.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Cover image" src="./images/monday.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is Monday!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I usally need a lot of warm up time on Monday mornings and get productive on Mondays only towards the second half of the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Monday's yak shaving on Friday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to have a productive Monday, I make sure I have a prioritised list ready on …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Cover image" src="./images/monday.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is Monday!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I usally need a lot of warm up time on Monday mornings and get productive on Mondays only towards the second half of the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Monday's yak shaving on Friday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to have a productive Monday, I make sure I have a prioritised list ready on my desk on Friday evening. This is something I started practising recently, and has been working very well for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the weekend, I make sure I don't do any work related things and start work directly on Monday morning. The prioritised list helps me with relevant context to start the Monday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Analog notes taking&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My note taking method is analog. I jot down notes on pen and paper. My biggest satisfaction over the week is crossing off the todos from my list and tossing the paper into the dustbin. This feels like such a big relief from a mental load point of view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How does it help me&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was wondering if the analog way would help me be productive. In this digital age, should I too not make a digital move? How will I access the information from everywhere?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a good memory, but when dealing with multipel things and constant context switching and interruption driven development, it is only natural that I cannot track each and every thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With my analog notes taking, I make it a point to visit my notes every now and then. I write my important todos in a different paper, while writing the random things as they pop up in another paper. This can be multiple papers for a given day based on the workload. When I revisit my notes every now and then, the frequency I am talking about is atleast twice a week, it helps me refresh my memory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then start writing them over again in a new paper and recategorise and reprioritise. Writing over again and revisiting does help me stay on top of things, and there is very little chance to miss out or forget things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Isn't digital better&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With digital ways, it does help me track notes from outside, when I am not on my work desk. But I have little motivation to revisit my digital todos over and over again and hence things sit idle or unvisited for a long time. During this time, my memory is replaced with other things and I forget.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There might be better digital ways, offcourse I am not debating on that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But my choice is analog notes taking, highlight with colors, revisit and get things done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am very productive, and I can totally recommed this way of doing incase you are looking to find a productive way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy Monday! :) &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Leadership"></category><category term="priorities"></category><category term="time"></category></entry></feed>